# **Bulut Karakaya**

bulutk@gmail.com | www.bulutk.com

Phone: +44 (7470) 890039 | Skype: bulutkarakaya

### **Career Objective**

I'm an ambitious gameplay programmer with 10+ years of experience. My focus areas are core gameplay and networking using Unity and Unreal engines. I co-founded two indie game studios and currently, I'm working to create inspiring games in the UK. My current objective is to find ways to merge my interest in machine learning with the game development to open new possibilities.

#### **Work Experience**

May 2008

July 2018 - Present	Senior Gameplay Programmer – Jagex Ltd, Cambridge, United Kingdom  • Working on an unannounced Action-RPG game using Unreal Engine 4, C++.
	• Working on core combat, player and AI navigation as well as high-level networking.
	<ul> <li>Collaborating with game designers, decide on the architectural changes needed for their requirements.</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Creating proposals to handle our tech depts, improve our systems and fix performance issues.</li> </ul>
March 2017 - June 2018	Lead Unity Programmer - Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland
	<ul> <li>Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command, for IOS and Android using Unity, C#</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Responsible for creating technical plans and give time estimates for designs.</li> </ul>
	• Line manager for a senior and a mid-level programmer.
	<ul> <li>Have regular meetings with non-tech teams, making sure their objectives are aligned with ours.</li> </ul>
Oct 2016 - March 2017	Senior Unity Programmer – Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland
	<ul> <li>Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command, for IOS and Android using Unity, C#</li> </ul>
Nov 2014 – May 2016	Co-founder / Technical Director – Pera Games, Istanbul, Turkey
	<ul> <li>Created Overfall a rogue-like RPG title for Steam using Unity, C#</li> </ul>
	• Responsible for all the programming and creating the tools for our non-technical team to create characters, spells,
	environments and encounters without programmer help.
	<ul> <li>Organised and moderate some of the high-level game design meetings.</li> </ul>
	• Launched the game on Steam, %93 positive feedback at the end of the first month.
	• Presented Overfall at Unite'16 as a showcase game.
March 2014 - Sept 2014	Project Partner – GriPati Digital Entertainment, Istanbul, Turkey
	<ul> <li>Created Egg Fight a multiplayer fast-paced fighting game for IOS and Android using Unity, C#</li> </ul>
	• Responsible for all the programming and partial game design.
	• Used Unity to create the game client and GameSparks for the backend.
Jan 2013 – Feb 2014	Co-founder / Technical Director – Tart Games, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Created <b>Kixel</b> a multiplayer 3d soccer game for Facebook and IOS using Unity, C#
	• Kixel reached over 2 million users in one year.
	• Responsible for most of the gameplay programming and leading a team of 6 people.
	• Used Unity as our game engine and Node.js with MongoDB for the backend.
Aug 2012 – April 2013	Software Engineer – Tart New Media, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Responsible for optimising and developing the backend of gamification engine.
C4 2010 D 2011	• Used Node.js and MongoDB.
	• Line manager for 2 junior programmers.
Sept 2010 – Dec 2011	Gameplay Programmer – Gravi, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Worked on Gravi Floor, an interactive playground which features various mini-games.
I 2000 A 2000	• Created prototypes using Unity, C#
June 2009 – Aug 2009	Prototype Intern – Stupid Fun Club, Berkeley, USA
	• Stupid Fun Club is an entertainment think tank company created by Will Wright
Inl. 2007 Sant 2007	• Worked on prototypes for unannounced projects using C# and XNA.
July 2007 – Sept 2007	Internship – Microsoft Corporation, Redmond, USA  • The First intern accented to US office from a Turkish university
	<ul> <li>The First intern accepted to US office from a Turkish university.</li> <li>Worked as software developer in test for Microsoft Office</li> </ul>
	worked as software developer in test for wherosoft Office
Education	
May 2010	Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) - Entertainment Technologies Center, Pittsburgh, U.S.A
	Master Of Entertainment Technology (MET)
	<ul> <li>Created SurfaceScapes, a D&amp;D experience on Microsoft Surface table. Presented in GDC'10 and PAX East.</li> </ul>
	• TA for Building Virtual Worlds course.
Mov. 2008	Cabanai University (CII) Istanbul Tunkay

Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science and Engineering (CS)
 TA for VA433 3D Modeling and VA434 3D Animation course.

Sabanci University (SU), Istanbul, Turkey

#### Bulut Karakaya – bulutk@gmail.com

## Certificates

Aug 2020 Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera)

**Skills** 

**Proficient:** C#, C++

**Engines & Libraries:** Unity, Unreal Engine 4

**Version Control:** Git, Perforce

Language: English (fluent), Turkish (Native)

Others: Maya, AfterEffects, PhotoShop (for programmer art)

#### **Interests**

Certified diver, tango dancer, Wing-Tsun practitioner, snowboarder and aerial acrobat. I also like games ( $\underline{Link}$ ) and reading ( $\underline{Link}$ ).